Simkin, William E. Arbitration Files 5784
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William E. Simkin Arbitration Files
1940-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Simkin, William E.
5784
18 cubic feet
18 linear ft.
Case files, collective labor agreements.
Collective labor agreements
3124645
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 03, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5143: Anna Weinstock Schneider Papers 5548: I. Robert Feinberg Arbitration Records 5780/200: ILGWU Miscellany 5784: William E. Simkin Arbitration Files 6004 OHM: NAA History Committee Oral History Interview Masters 6205: NAA Committee Files
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Simkin, William E.
3124645
- Ad Hoc Arbitration (Box 1)
  - Aberfoyle and TWU, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    1 Decision
  - Alan Wood and USA, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    5 decisions
  - Aleo Manufacturing Company and TWU, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    3 Decisions
  - Allegheny Ludlum and USA, 1945-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    1945 and 1959 4 decisions
  - American Bridge and USA, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    2 decisions
  - American Lace Manufacturing and Amalgamated Lace Operatives, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    1 decision
  - American Locomotive and USA, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Sugar Refining and Packinghouse Workers, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Welding and USA, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    3 decisions
  - Arcrods Corporation and USA, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Armco Steel and USA, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Association Press and American Newspaper Guild, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    8 decisions
  - Atlas Drop Forge and UAW, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Baldwin-Lima-Hamilton and USA, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    12 decisions
  - Barrister Corporation, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baseball Salary, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bates Manufacturing Company and TWU, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bendex Products Division and Bendex Police Association, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Benson Public School and Teacher's Association, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bethlehem Steel (Bethlehem Pennsylvania) and USA, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bethlehem Steel (Sparrows Point Maryland) and USA, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    12 decisions Sp. Point?
  - Blue Swan Mills and ILGWU, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Blumenthal and American Bakery and Confectionary Workers, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brown Instrument Company and UE, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Camden Forge and Shipbuilders, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cardinal Boxes and Paperworkers, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Carnegie Illinois Steel Corporation and USA, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    4 decisions
  - Celanese Corporation and Textile Workers, 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    1940, 1959, and 1960 4 decisions
  - Chester Hospital and American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Chester Times and International Typographical Union, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cities Service Company and Teamsters, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Collier Owners and American Radio Association, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Columbia Broadcasting and Electrical Workers, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Communication for Cos and Agents and Association of Broadcast Workers, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Consumers Power Company and Utility Workers Organizing Committee, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Samuel Cowan and Sons and Luggage Workers, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Crane Company and International Union of Operative Potters, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Crown, Cork, and Seal and USA, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Crown, Cork, and Seal (Can division) and Machinists, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Crucible Steel (Pittsburgh) and USA, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Crucible Steel (Harrison, New Jersey) and USA, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Cuneo Eastern Press and Bookbinders, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Cuneo Eastern Press and Electrotypers, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cuneo Eastern Press and Press Assistants, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Cuneo Eastern Press and Mailers, 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    2 decisions 1947 and 1951
  - Cuneo Eastern Press and Machinists, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Ad Hoc Arbitration (Box 2)
  - Delaware Floor Products and Rubber Workers, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Detroit Free Press and Drivers and Handlers, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Duval Corporation and Electrical Workers, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Greyhound (Buffalo) and Amalgamated, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Greyhound (Pittsburgh) and Amalgamated, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Greyhound (N.E. etcetera) and Amalgamated, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Eastern Greyhound (Cleveland) and Amalgamated, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Eastern Greyhound (Boston) and Amalgamated, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Eastern Stainless Steel and USA, 1945-1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    20 decisions
  - Ellicott Company and USA, 1950-1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Feit and Amalgamated Insurance Fund, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fenestra and Teamsters, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Follansbee Steel Corporation and USA, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Franklinshire Worsted and TWA, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - French and Packing House Workers, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General Electric (Louisville) and IUE, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - GM and UAW, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Golden Belt and Textile Workers, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Goody mate and TWU, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Goodrich and URW, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Goodyear and URW (after regular service), 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Gralnick and Luggage Workers, 1950-1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hamilton Paper and Paper Workers, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Harrison Walker and Stone Workers, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Harmony Short Line and Amalgamated, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Harris and Sons and USA, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hartman Bindery and Bindery Workers, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Hellwig and TWUA, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Industrial Rayon and TWUA, 1947-1960 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    6 decisions
  - International News Service, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - J.K. Welding and Shipbuilders, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Johns-Manville and Glass Blowers Union, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Johnson Truck Lines and Teamsters, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Jones and Laughlin and USA, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Kaiser Aluminum and USA, 1959-1971 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Keasby and Mattison and UTW, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Kent Manufacturing Company and UTW, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Leather Goods and Truck Manufacturing Association, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Lehigh Structural Steel and USA, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Luzerne Company Gas and Electric and Utility Workers, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Lynchburg Foundry and USA, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Mack Manufacturing Company and AAA, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    19 decisions
  - Marana Public School and Education Association, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - L. Martin Company and Mine Workers, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Maryland Bolt and Nut and USA, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Merion Worsted Mills and Textile Workers, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Michigan Limestone and USA, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Milford Rivet and Machine and Machinists, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Model Shirt and Blouse and ACW, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Morton Company and Credit Store Employee Unions, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Ad Hoc Arbitration (Box 3)
  - National Gypsum and USA, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Publishing and Bookbinders, 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    3 decision
  - National Standard and USA, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Sugar Refinery and Refinery Workers, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - T. Nelson and Sons and Bookbinders, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - New York Shipbuilding Corporation and Shipbuilders, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ontario Dyeing Company and TWU, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Owens-Corning Fiberglass and Glass Blowers, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Owens-Corning Fiberglass and TWU, 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Palmer Shipping and Marine Engineers, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Parade Publications and Machinists, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Paragon Knitting Mills and Knit Goods Union, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania Foundry and Machine Company and USA, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania Forge Corporation and Machinists, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Penn-Jersey Shipbuilding and Draftsmen, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pennsylvania Greyhound Lines and Association, 1947-1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania Railroad and Clerks, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Phelps Dodge and United Electric Workers, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Philadelphia Brief Case Company and Luggage Workers, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Philadelphia Inquirer and Typos, 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Philadelphia Inquirer and Machinists, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Philco Corporation and Electrical Workers, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Pioneer Manufacturing Company and ILGWU, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Pittsburgh Screw and Bolt and USA, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Pittsburgh Steel (Allenport) and USA, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Pittsburgh Steel (Warren) and USA, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Prudential Insurance Company and Insurance Agents, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Publishers Association of New York City and Typos, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Publishers Association of New York City and Machinists, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Radio Corporation and Radio and Machine Workers, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Railroad Arbitration, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Ravenna Arsenal and USA, 1952-1959 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    10 decisions
  - Reading Street Railway and Amalgamated, 1947-1955 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    2 decisions 1947 and 1955
  - Real Silk Hosiery Mills and ILGWU, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Rheem Manufacturing Company and USA, 1950-1958 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Riegel Paper Company and Papermakers, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Rochester Telephone Company and Communication Workers, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    2 decisions 1958 and 1960
  - Rustless Iron and Steel and USA, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Joseph T. Ryerson and Son and USA, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Saybolt and Cleland Upholsterers, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Scranton Spring Brook Water Company and Utility Workers, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Seamless Rubber Company and Rubber Workers, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Sharpness Corporation and IUE, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Signal Knitting Mills and ILGWU, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Southeastern Greyhound and Amalgamated, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Southwestern Greyhound and Amalgamated, 1946-1960 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    2 decisions 1946 and 1960
  - Springfield Street Railway and Amalgamated, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Standard Steel Spring and USA, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Superior Industries and USA, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Ad Hoc Arbitration (Box 4)
  - Texas Company and Oil Workers, 1948-1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Textile Workers Union - Investment Case, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Triangle Publications and Photo Engravers, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Triple Cities Traction and Amalgamated, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - True Form Corset Company and ACW, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - True Temper and USA, 1960-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    16 decisions
  - Tucson Gas and Electric and Electrical Workers, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - TVA and 5 Unions, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tucson Unified School District and TEA, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - United Knitting Mills and ILGWU, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Unity Luggage Company and Luggage Workers, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Valley Mild and Iron and USA, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Union Carbide and USA, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Western Union and UTW, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Ad Hoc Arbitration (Box 5)
  - Frontier Airlines and Flight Attendants, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    1 decisions
  - Tucson Unified School District and Classified Employees, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Western Airlines and Air Transport Union, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Western Union and UTW, 1972-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    15 decisions
- Ad Hoc Arbitration New Contract or Renewal of Contract Cases (Box 6)
  - Western Union and UTW, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Wilkenning Manufacturing Company and United Electric, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Windsor Manufacturing Company and TWU, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Yellow Truck and Coach and UAW, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Yorkshire Knitting Mills and WU, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Youngstown Sheet and Tube and USA, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    2 decisions 1954 and 1956
  - Sunnyside School District, Number L2 and Education Association, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    9 decisions
  - Steel Incentive Case (Simkin, Seward, and Garrett), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- New Contract or Renewal of Contract Cases (Simkin only) (Box 7)
  - Associated Press and American Newspaper Guild, 1951-1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    2 decisions 1951 and 1954
  - Associated Press and UTW, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Clifton Yarn Mills and Textile Workers, 1942-1949 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Colt Patent Firearms and UE, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut Company and Amalgamated, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - R.B. Dutt Company and TWU, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Greyhound Fact Finding Panel and Amalgamated, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Graphic Arts Association and Pressmen, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Gulf States Utilities and Electric Employee Services, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Harm-Bromley Company and TWU, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - United News Service and Guild, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Milwaukee Street Railway and Amalgamated, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Paper Box Manufacturing and Paper Workers, 1940-1942 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    2 decisions 1940 and 1942
  - Papermill Manufacturing Company and TWU, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Philco Company and IUE, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Reading Street Railway and Amalgamated, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Royersford Needle Works and Hosiery Workers, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Joseph Scale yard Company and TWU, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - John B. Stetson Company and Hat Workers, 1941-1946 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    2 decisions 1941 and 1946
  - Todd Shipyards and Shipbuilders, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Triple Cities Traction and Amalgamated, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Tucson Gas and Electric and Electricians, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - TVA and Salaried Panel, 1971-1977 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    2 decisions 1971 and 1977
  - United Press and Telegraphers, 1948-1954 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    2 decisions 1948 and 1954
  - Washington School District and Education Association, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Special Industrial Panels of Puerto Rico, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Western Airlines and Pilots, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - General Motors and UAW (G. Allen Dash only) (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Box 8)
  - Full Fashioned Hosiery Workers (prior to and after W.E.S. Service in this industry) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Allegheny Ludlum and USA, 1946-1952 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    25 decisions
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Simkin only) (Box 9)
  - American Viscose and TWU, 1947-1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    375 decisions
  - American Viscose (Sylvania Division) and TWU, 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    18 decisions
  - American Viscose (Film Division) and TWU, 1958-1961 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - American Viscose (Marcuse Hook) and TWU, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Simkin only) (Box 10)
  - Goodyear-Akron only and URW, 1945-1947 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    121 decisions
  - Goodyear- Akron only and URW (memos), 1945-1947 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Goodyear Company wide and URW, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    100 decisions
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Simkin only) (Box 11)
  - Goodyear Company-wide and URW, 1948-1951 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    416 decisions
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Simkin and Dash) (Box 12)
  - Goodyear - Company-wide and URW, 1955-1958 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    500 decisions
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Box 13)
  - Goodyear (Company-Wide) - Simkin and Dash, 1958-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    124 decisions
  - Goodyear (Company-wide) Simkin and Dash (Awards), 1957-1959 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    256 decisions
  - Sun Ship and Shipbuilders (Simkin only), 1944-1949 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    194 decisions
  - Cramp Ship and Shipbuilders, 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    59 decisions
  - Ad Hoc Grievances (Not included earlier) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Mack Manufacturing Company and UAW, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Pennsylvania Rubber Company and URW, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Simkin only) (Box 14)
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - Balto, 1946-1954 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    67 decisions
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - Sparrows Point, 1943-1954 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    97 decisions
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - Brooklyn, 1945-1949 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    43 decisions
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - 56th Street, 1945-1949 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    14 decisions
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - Boston, 1946-1948 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - Fairfield, 1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - Hoboken, 1945-1948 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - Quincy, 1946-1949 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    65 decisions
  - Bethlehem Ship and Shipbuilders - Staten Island, 1946-1954 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    45 decisions
  - United States Rubber Company and Rubber Workers (Box 14, Folder 10)
    28 decisions
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Simkin only) (Box 15)
  - Honeywell and Local 1145 Teamsters, 1970-1982 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    1492 decisions
  - National Can and USA, 1956-1960 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    51 decisions
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Simkin only) (Box 16)
  - Firestone and URW, 1952-1961 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    115
  - Crucible Steel and USA, 1953-1960 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    91 decisions
  - Kaiser Aluminum and Chemical Company and URW, 1970-1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    7 decisions
- Named in Contract for Grievances (Simkin only) (Box 17)
  - Sun Ship and Shipbuilders, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    64 decisions 1945-?
  - Armour Company and Meat Cutters, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Copies of Various Labor Agreements (Box 18)
  - Copies of Various Labor Agreements (Box 18, Folder 1)